let's look at the solution to our
message passing versus shared memory
quiz if we have one core initializing an
array and then all others reading the
entire array data distribution the
number of lines of code you need to do
it in message passing
is significant
the number of lines of code we need for
that in shared memory
is really zero lines of code because
once the array is initialized in memory
others can simply read it they don't
need to really distribute the data in
any way in contrast in message passing
the core that initializes the array now
needs to send it explicitly to all the
other cores and the other cores need to
receive it explicitly so there is
definitely
more lines of code in message passing
than in shared memory
once you have the data distribution
for shared memory you don't need to do
anything for it for message passing you
need to send and receive
synchronization that makes sure that the
array is initialized before we get to
read it
adds how many lines of code
in message passing
it adds zero lines of code because the
sends and receives
that we needed to do to distribute the
data already ensure
that until we receive the array we
cannot read it so when we get to read it
after the receive we know that it's been
already initialized because the send
happens after the initialization in
shared memory however
while the initialization is happening
the other threads could just begin
reading it so we need to
add some explicit synchronization now to
make sure that the readers wait while
the initialization is happening so we
here have more than zero lines of code
in this case the message passing code is
simpler as far as synchronization is
concerned than the shared memory code
this is typically going to be what
happens between shared memory and
message passing message passing needs to
distribute data but in doing so it also
synchronizes
shared memory doesn't need to distribute
data but if synchronization is needed
after the distribution it needs to add
explicit code to do that